Sweet. All right. So guys, this is the intro to team building.
And I say intro because this is a really deep topic and, you know,
building teams, managing people systems, SOPs, all of that stuff.
It can get really deep as, as you guys know, um,
with people with existing teams or, you know, worked in agencies and stuff.
But, um, I'll try to cover as much as I can. And then I'll leave, uh,
about like 15 minutes or so to do like an a m a And let me actually just put a
little timer on here so we can make sure we're on time.
All right, so who is this training for video marketers?
I think there's a bunch of them here. Coaches, affiliates,
agency owners, and brand owners. Raise your hand if you are one of those guys.
One of those girls too. I see some, some girls here. Awesome.
Love it. Yeah, I mean, this is, this is the bread and butter.
This is what we're talking about here.
So if you wanna hire creative people to do the creative work in your business,
this is for you. All right.
So what you'll gain from this presentation and training, you'll learn strategy,
how to build a creative operation. If you,
even if you have zero experience in you're a one man show,
raise your hand if you're a one man show. Nice.
I love that. Couple on
Here. Yeah, for sure.
Yeah. Tips and tricks to learn.
The dos and don'ts to hiring creatives and where to find them. Lastly,
key lessons from my mistakes of building a 50 person team.
That was a nightmare. Um,
I was, I was crying internally for you when you were literally mentioning that.
Of course, I've known that from before, but anytime you've brought it up,
I'm always like, Ugh,
I know. It's, it was rough. Uh, we'll, we'll share some stuff from that,
but my name's John Felix Reyes. Uh, I'm a f I'm the founder of two companies.
E-Comm Vids is a video production and ads Arex,
which is a template and training business for creatives. Uh,
we've shot over 7,000 videos in five years. Uh,
I've had 10 years direct response marketing. Um, I didn't,
I wasn't always like a video guy.
I actually started off as a landing page designer. And, um,
like I would build funnels for my supplement brand,
which we grew to eight figures. Um, but I'm a father, husband,
self-taught, you know, learn by just f*****g up a bunch.
And I love comedy and entertaining. So that's kind of me in a nutshell.
Here's some sales that we've generated from our, um, uh, a agency,
creative agency. And these are some photos that we had when we had,
like a big operation. We had sets, we had, you know,
tons of employees working in-house.
We were like pumping out stuff like clockwork. It was, it was nuts.
Hundreds of videos a month. This is the ads direct side.
So we basically like templatize top performing ads and make it really easy for
editors to, um, to create high converting ads.
Quick little story about me, um, a picture on the left is,
uh, me in 2016 when I was this bachelor,
really living it up, partying, making a s**t ton of money.
I was living in like the premium spot in Orange County, California.
I was doing the girls, doing the drugs, just getting fricking hammered.
And it was like the best. And like, at
Least you admit it.
I I, could you not? Like I had worked my whole life. You know, we had,
I had been building this company for like four years with two other partners,
and finally when we started making money, I was like, it is time to go.
So basically what happened was I kind of, uh,
partied myself to, uh, to the ground and, uh,
my business partners ended up kicking me out of the business that I actually
started with them.
And so we were like on the cusp of becoming an eight figure company,
and one day they just sat me down. They're like, Hey, John, um,
we're gonna buy you out. And I was like, what the, what the hell? You know,
like I was, you know, my, my monthly expenses were like 15 grand, 15, 20 grand.
I was like, um, what's gonna happen now? They're like, eh,
we'll give you a little bit of money,
and you just gotta figure it out from here.
So that was kind of my wake up call in my life.
And pretty much from there I hit rock bottom. You know, I lost everything.
I had met my girlfriend, who was now my wife at the time.
And pretty much from there it was just like building myself back up,
like changing my identity from being this like partier drug addict to
like being an actual good person. And that takes a lot of work.
So that was really painful. But now I have two kids and, uh,
they're a lot of fun. And that's a whole nother journey.
So anybody here have kids? Raise your hand. What's going on? Oh, dude.
Parents know what's up. Yeah, it is hard.
I think like, having kids is way harder than like running a business. Um,
so here is my 50 person employee tree map.
When it was really like cranking things out on the, um,
video production agency side. We were running, like, we had a lot of, um,
we had 25 editors. We had, um, you know,
tons of video production teams. We had script writers,
we had project managers. All this, it was, it was nuts.
And you can see me on the very top here, just like losing his mind.
'cause I had so many people underneath me.
She put like a little, like a zombie emoji on top of that or something.
Right, exactly. Um, that's basically what I was, I was a slave to my business.
Um, so in actually 2021,
I ended up downsizing my entire business. So this was really hard.
So I went from like having 50 people to basically like,
less than 10, like 10 people.
And so you can see our big warehouse where we had all the sets and stuff,
we've moved out of that thing. And it was really depressing. Um,
actually this guy right here on the right was like one of my initial like
founders. And we ended up buying him out of the company too.
So it was really hard to dismantle a big company to a
small one. You know, it's like, it's easy to grow,
but then like to cut back and like, go from 50 to 10, you're like, holy crap,
I have to like, rethink and restructure everything. So that was a basic,
you know, that was the last year and a half.
We've been operating at a much more lean level.
And that's kind of what this presentation is about, is operating super lean.
So why do you need a creative team? I think it's so,
so important to just get your why's in place, right? So we want to like,
have intention before we do anything, and we like invest in things.
So what is the intention of the work you're trying to do?
And why are you trying to do it?
So here are three different potential scenarios that could fit into your why.
And I know that there's people here who can relate brand owners, coaches,
agency owners, and creatives, right?
So let's talk about brand owners and coaches. If you want a creative team,
you can scale paid ads better, right? You want to bring things in-house,
gain control over the creative process.
You don't wanna rely on external agencies. It could be really expensive,
quality control, all that stuff. If you have a creative team in-house,
you can have an unfair creative advantage because you are just churning things
out. You can have a reliable, creative team who can think for you.
I think that's one of the biggest things, um, to have a creative team for it.
You can focus on what you are best at in the business and not get your fingers
in all the creative parts. It's like me trying to do a lot of copywriting. Like,
I can do it, but I don't wanna do it. Like, that's it.
It's just two different brains, right? Um,
you can potentially exit for a large amount 'cause you have the team members.
Uh, you can have efficient creative systems that,
and teams that pump out high converting assets weekly.
So if you're an agency owner, you can offer more services to clients.
So that's one thing that I've had a lot of people ask me about is like, I,
I wanna offer video, you know, as a creative, uh, as an agency.
And I think like these days you've gotta have,
you've gotta have control over that, right? As you guys all know,
I've taken Will's course, it like absolutely changed my life, uh,
changed the way that I operate as a, uh, creative agency. So it's like, just,
we'll get there, but this is super important if you're an agency owner.
And lastly, if you are a creative, is there any creatives here? Like,
raise your hand. That's
A good question. I don't know that we,
we do have a few creative first individuals in the community. Would any,
would anyone consider themselves like a, um,
copywriter or a,
or a videographer or something like that first before they'd consider themselves
a like ad buyer agency? Something like that. Creative outta necessity.
Yeah. Luke said copywriter first. Yeah, that's true actually. Kurt. Kurt is, um,
Kurt is for sure a creative first. Uh, he has a,
a guitar sort of instruction program.
And so he's learning the digital marketing side of his business.
I love it. Yeah. Sometimes we're just forced to do those things, you know,
like I was forced to do operations and all,
and things that I'm not that great at. Um,
but leaning into your strengths is really what you wanna do.
And then have people who are better than you to, uh, to run the show.
Can I ask you a quick question on that?
Why do you think it is so important to optimize internally towards strengths and
build team around air quotes, weakness, or not an area of strength?
Yeah. Um, well, I think it just comes down to efficiency at the end of the day,
because someone who's gifted and talented at let's say editing or videography or
copywriting, right?
They're gonna be able to run circles around somebody who isn't right.
Necessarily talented. And for me, example,
like me and my wife we're like the perfect partners because I handle like
creative and execution. And then she's like operations and finance.
So it's like when you put my creative brain into operations, it just melts down.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
And sometimes when you put like a logical thinker into a creative atmosphere,
they shut down. Mm-hmm.
And so it's really important to balance those two sides of the brain and have
like, you know,
it it just different parts of the business with different requirements. Yeah.
And with that, it it, you know,
'cause there is a lot of like media buyer led agencies here in the group, right?
Like, if their zone of genius is the media buying,
it's getting the support that allows them to be in their zone of genius.
I agree to your point.
Yeah. And it's so crucial.
I think that that's the hardest thing is connecting the media buyer and the
strategist with the creative team. Because if they're not in communication,
like the whole thing goes to s**t because that alignment is everything.
Cool.
So we'll talk about that. So things to remember before building a creative team.
Building a team is not easy, all right? Is very stressful.
You're dealing with people, not robots. Okay.
I had a big team and I was almost treating everyone like a robot. It's like,
okay, you're gonna just write this type of thing, you're just gonna edit this.
And I kind of compartmentalized everybody. And then, you know,
people get bored of that. And, um, and it's also really,
really difficult to manage when it's like one job.
'cause you gotta keep them busy all the time's. Guilty.
That's guilty of that too, by the way. Yep, yep.
Yeah, absolutely. People require management and training. Like,
if you're a one man show, you take on one additional person, you're, it's like,
oh, like your life just changed. Like, you, it's like you, you, like,
you just took on a kid and you've got to work with them and guide them
and do all that stuff. So leadership comes into play. Top talent,
it costs money. Um, you know, right off the bat,
like we didn't have a lot of money to pay for talent,
so we kind of had to build things from the ground.
But eventually we found out that like,
you can fi you can find really good people, obviously,
like depending on where in the world, um,
they're gonna cost more because they have more experience,
but they're gonna add way more value in your business.
People have different beliefs and values.
So when you start to have a bigger team,
there's like conflict that could happen depending on, you know,
so you have to be very neutral about stuff.
Like you can p**s a lot of people off. Um,
I've had very opinionated employees in the past that have caused a s**t ton of
like, headaches and, um, you know, firing people is not fun.
So just being mindful of that when you start to get into that process.
So the rewards of building a team,
thriving business that can run without you satisfaction and seeing others
working with each other to accomplish a common goal. I, I love teamwork.
I love seeing other people, you know, have input and like,
have things that I didn't see, like catch, just like contribute to the,
to the overall goal. It's like, damn, we made it, we did it. Um,
another thing is incentivizing and sharing your winnings with the team and
scalability beyond you.
So my six mistakes, building a creative team and how to avoid them. This is,
this probably can go to like 60 to be honest, but, um,
but yeah, we'll just summarize it to six. Alright.
Mistake number one is hiring too fast. When I started my company,
you know, we were in the startup phase and it was like booming. You know,
we're a very, we're one of the first businesses to do what we did,
but I didn't have operations experience,
so I thought bring on more people would get more done and make more money at the
same time. It's not true. You gotta protect your margins.
Hiring people is very costly and time consuming. So do this instead.
Hire slow,
be methodical about your first hires and really vet them before committing to
them and having them commit to you. Right?
This is so important because it's so much easier to hire someone than it is to
fire someone. Mm-hmm. Um, I don't know about you will,
but I've held people on in my business for a little too long and then
like having that difficult conversation later on, it is not
Fun. Not only that,
but it's detrimental because of the lack of performance while they're there.
Yeah. You know? And then how do,
how does the rest of the team see that individual?
Absolutely. They see it. Yeah. Yeah. Man, it's like,
you're only as strong as your weakest link. And man,
I had a lot of those and it was just like,
one person can bring the whole team down.
Yeah.
Mistake number two, hiring unqualified people.
So I'll be honest, I was lazy and competent.
I hired friends of friends who just needed jobs,
and I just took their word for it. And so this can work for low level tasks,
but isn't good for high level execution. You know, I was in this position,
I was like, I just need to bring people on. Who do you know? Who do you know?
And I was like, come on, let's do this. Um,
so over time I realized you gotta hire qualified people.
That was one of the biggest breakthroughs that I think I had as well,
like five or so years ago, was committing to that. Like, I, not wanting,
I didn't want, you know, I didn't wake up one day and I was like,
I'm gonna be a master sort of HR hiring and recruiter. Right.
But as you go through some of those mistakes, like you've mentioned,
you're like, wow,
this is one of the most important things that I could be doing every day. Yeah,
yeah. Like, is the way that I filter talent.
Right? Absolutely. And in the beginning,
you don't really know what is good and what's not good. Yeah.
And so what you can, I think what's really important, and we'll just distill it,
is like asking the right questions in the interview process. Like values,
I think is really important Experience and like giving them potential scenarios
of like, what would you do in this situation? Like,
you really wanna measure for like, critical thinking. Yeah. And, um,
like their ability to kind of think on their feet too. But, um,
I think putting people to the test and seeing how they perform is critical.
Like, don't just take anyone's word for it. Don't take a resume, you know, and,
and be like, okay, you look good. It's like, no, if you're an editor,
I'm gonna bring you on. I'm gonna like, be like, okay,
I want you to edit three of these ads and three different styles,
and I want you to explain to me why you did those choices. Mm-hmm. Like,
that's really important.
Yeah. Test projects are a great part of finding qualified people.
Absolutely. And yeah, I'll share some stuff in the, uh,
later on to the group that like, you guys can share with your, you know,
if you're hiring certain people. But, um,
mistake number three is no training systems. And I think as a startup, you know,
you're like, you don't have these things built up. You know,
it's like you expect people to just figure things out, but it's like they're,
they need to be led. So we're startups.
Everything was super reactive and moving so fast.
There was little time to ever go backwards to do systems and training.
And it's like, yo, we, the client is doing this. We need, we, we need results.
We need to place people in. It's like, just, just figure it out. Right?
I feel like in the agency world is very, very fast moving like that. Mm-hmm. Um,
so I didn't really understand SOPs and systems until a year into the business.
Um, and then I read this book called Build a Business, not a Job.
And this thing really opened up my eyes to like,
how to systemize creating an ultimate business system, like creating SOPs,
like documenting every little thing so that you have a training manual for, um,
for your employees and future employees. SOPs became my life,
by the way.
Same. Same. We know, we pushed the sop, everybody here knows.
Yeah, dude, it's everything. Yeah. Do this instead.
Build SOPs and trainings from the start.
I think this is like more of like a discipline, um,
that I've kind of picked up over the years is like,
document your processes and record everything while it's fresh. Okay.
It's so much harder to go back and remember what you did. Because like,
you can always, if you do it the first time,
you can always go back and improve on the trains.
But like to try to recall what was it that I did there, you know? Mm-hmm.
It's like, just kinda like, if you're training someone, just record the session,
you know? And then, and then you can always go back to it.
Mistake number four, poor leadership. Um,
I'm not a natural born leader. And, uh, I also didn't hire natural born leaders.
So this created a very chill work environment. Super chill, you know, like, uh,
which is fun. Like, I like having fun and I like being chill.
But what happened was there was no sense of urgency and ownership to problems.
So this led to poor accountability and quality control. Like,
I had to learn the hard way. It's like I wanted everyone to be my friend,
but realizing that like, you've gotta step in there when s**t goes wrong.
Like you've got, you've gotta have consequences. And, um, if that, if they keep,
if you keep going in that direction, like they won't respect you. Um,
the only real leader in the company was my wife at that point. She's like,
she had the balls, you know, she's like, yeah. But, um, but yeah,
that's where the balance is. Um,
so do this instead level up your leadership and find leaders. Anybody here,
like, I'm just curious. Uh, natural born leaders here, like LED teams.
Yeah. What? Like, in, in,
Totally.
That's cool. I love that, man. Um, that's
Where I gravitate towards naturally is just that area.
Like the figuring out how people work.
I love it. For sure. Yeah. It's fascinating. I mean, I've,
I've learned to love it and, you know, it's practice, but, um, no matter,
no matter what, if you're gonna lead a team,
you're gonna have to become a leader. Step outta your comfort zone.
Being a leader will test your resilience without a doubt. Um,
I think it's really important to test and interview for leadership qualities in
your hires, right? Like putting them in, like problem solutions, scenarios. Um,
because great leaders will take accountability. They'll take initiative,
find solutions, and then have a vision. Not every employee is gonna have that.
All right. And like,
you'll find the little leaders in there who have those qualities and it's like,
okay, I'm gonna position you in a,
in a higher position where you can look over people.
Yeah. A quick little thought on that. Funny enough,
this is actually a saying that my dad gave me like probably 30 years ago.
Um, true leaders don't wait to be appointed a leader. Hmm. You know,
they just show up that way. And, um, you know, uh, I think it's a,
to your point about trying to find individuals like that when you're hiring,
so test and interview for leadership qualities. I think, uh,
a really good example of that is how can you,
how can you identify someone who naturally steps up into that long before you
really need for them to correct? Um,
so I just thought that was very relevant to what you were sharing.
Absolutely, man.
And I have tried to like freaking push people to become leaders. I'm like,
just freaking do it, you know, and won because like, they're not natural leader.
Like they're introverts or, you know, you can't make like a creative,
super creative guy into a, a, a project manager. Like, I've tried doing that,
and it's like, no, sometimes you just, they just need to be individual roles,
but then have a strong leader kind of motivate them and get them moving. So,
yeah, I agree. Mistake number five, not reinvesting in the team. All right.
So we had really low margins, so we didn't invest into like,
other additional opportunities, um, workshops, equipment for the team.
And I was doing most of the training, so,
but I was also trying to keep the company from, from dying. So, um,
this is really important. Just invest in your team's personal growth, right?
It's really easy to do this. Schedule monthly trainings with the team. I think,
I mean, being, being here in in Will's program is one of those things that like,
you've already determined that you are a learner and an earner like it,
it's amazing being part of these communities.
Like if you're part of a company or you're, or, or you're a one-man show, like,
just that constant feed being surrounded by like-minded, growth-minded people.
It's just, it's fantastic. And a lot of the times employees will like,
come from, you know, different backgrounds. They're not really in this like,
high performance mindset. Mm-hmm. So you kind of have to push them into,
into that and their eyes will open because as an entrepreneur, like dude,
when you got hooked onto entrepreneurship, like, you're like, dude,
this is mind blowing. Like your eyes open, but never look back. Right? Yeah,
exactly. So yeah, really important. I think what you're doing here will,
is amazing. Thanks Keith. Thank you. Um, last, last mistake.
Keeping partners on for too long. Um,
I started the business with two other partners, ended up,
and now it's just me and my wife, uh, who own the business.
So these partners helped me get to a certain stage,
but eventually had to separate because they were no longer adding value at the
stage we were at. Anybody here have business partners? Yeah,
we have business partners for sure. Yeah.
Anybody gone through like difficult business partner relationships? Okay.
Yeah. Yeah, dude, it's, it's f*****g hard man.
'cause it gets all legally and stuff and hard emotion. Yeah.
Super emotional man. Um, so yeah, I mean, I've been bought out,
you know,
from other partners and I've bought out partners and it's just a difficult
conversation, man. I think it's just really important to like set the, um, set,
set the expectations, um, from the get go. You know, finding a comp,
finding a partner who actually does compliment you, I think is really key.
It's almost like a marriage, right? I think, uh, to avoid resentment. Yeah.
Resentment builds a lot in partnerships.
I don't know if anybody agrees with that, but let's say one person,
you're doing more than the other person. And when I get like, dude,
I'm bringing this, that, and you're not doing that, like,
that was my conversation. I'm like, bro, like we're 50 50 on this. I, and like,
I'm doing 10 times more value. Hmm. So that I could not like, live with myself.
Like knowing that. And, um, eventually we just had to part and I was like, okay,
here it is. Uh, just be clear about it. Um, all right.
So let's move on to creative jobs. All right. We've got copywriting,
creative strategy, graphic design, web design, videography, video editing,
animation. Anybody here do any of those things already?
Or you're just doing them because you have to do them? Or maybe offer it?
Offer it as well? Or offer it? Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
These are all the creative jobs like that I've learned to do as a creative. But,
um, these are basically, if you want to build your business around creative,
like these are the hires that you're gonna be focusing on. Non-creative jobs,
project management, muted buying, web development, operations, finance,
logistics, analytics, customer service. So it's like two separate,
I would say types of hires, but they all go hand in hand.
So we'll talk about that in a second. Big question here, right?
Do I outsource or bring in-house? Um, that, that was always kind of my thing. I,
I like bringing everyone in-house, like literally physically in the house.
So I'm like, oh, more people. It's fun, you know, we get to do events and stuff,
but, um, not smart if, uh, if they're not needed. So outsource contract,
someone who isn't gonna be needed in the business full-time.
'cause you're one-off projects needed for specific use for the business.
This will keep your overhead lean and require much less management.
Bring them in-house if you plan on utilizing them in the business daily.
All right. Ban issues with outsourcing when we're trying to scale. Yeah.
It's, it's hard to rely on outsource contract 'cause they're all doing different
things too. You know, they're not fully committed to you.
You can't rely on them to, you know, Hey, I need this done tonight. You know,
you can't drive over their house and be like, Hey, let's work on this. Mm-hmm.
So there, there's, there's advantages obviously to having someone in-house.
A lot more control. Um, and I, I prefer, I mean,
it really just depends on your business.
So if you're just starting out, um, I would say, you know,
if you guys are running ads, everyone here is running ads for the most part,
right? I would say number one hire is definitely gotta be a video editor.
Does anybody here have a video editor? Sick Joe Raises hand.
Dusty. Awesome. Ki yeah. Quite a few. Yeah. I think,
you know, there's all different types of video editors and the quality,
but I'm telling you, if you can find one really good video editor,
they're have got four. He's got like four kids and four video editors. Man.
Five kids. Five. Five kids or five video editors? Both. Oh, both.
I was kidding. That's, he's like, my kids are the video editors.
No kidding. No kids yet. No kids
Yet. Okay. Five.
Five in the future.
Oh yeah. Anyone? Yeah. Five or, um, Upwork.
I'll talk about where to hire video editors in a second. But, um,
one thing to remember about video editors, man, like, um,
one really strong video editor can make up for like five basic average video
editors. Um, you want a video editor who can think critically isn't and,
and isn't just like a, an executor, alright? Um,
someone who you can have conversations with, who you can give a call to,
who you can walk through the videos with.
That's what I do with my video editors. It's like, Hey, dude, like,
you're almost there, but let's just kind of go through this step by step. Um,
also, if you guys are outsourcing your content U G C platforms, you know,
you working with other agencies, influencers, you're gonna need a video editor.
You cannot rely so much on like U G C creators to produce
high quality ads. Like they're not editors at the end of the day.
Like not all of them are. Um,
so having that guy in your back pocket can take footage, mash it up,
do all that stuff. I I train video editors on that. Um, number two,
videographer and content creators, you're shooting in-house content.
This will give the creative team member enough work to plan, shoot, and edit.
I think like this is one of those things, you know, if you,
if you're not shooting content like that often, I don't think it's required.
But I think partnering up with like content creators,
like getting them on like a monthly deal,
especially if you're like an E-com brand, um, I think is really valuable.
'cause they're gonna, they're gonna grow with you.
They're gonna learn your product and they're just gonna get better over time.
Um, so yeah, that's my recommendation there.
Hey, John, quick question on the video at number one there for U G C. Yep.
I think a lot of the people here,
my value is if you are going to do your own edits to really get the assets
like direct, direct response optimized and stuff, do you have specific,
maybe something even templated or something that you're giving to the U G C
creators to just make it as friendly and ready for your future edits since you
have so much experience with doing those videos? Like,
is there anything you point them towards? Yeah.
The, the creators themselves? Absolutely. Yeah. So depending on like,
the deal and structure that you have with them, um,
I think it really comes down to the brief. All right.
So it's like being very clear and explicit about what you want the video
to be and the style and the inspiration. And you know,
a lot of times people will be like, just, you know, use your creativity.
It's like, no, don't f*****g do that. Like, um, as the strategist, you know,
you gotta, you gotta be very, like, very clear on what you want.
And I always suggest, okay,
let's say there's like some ads that you're getting inspo from,
from like foreplay or something, right? It's like, okay, copy this video.
Here's the script,
here's the B-roll here are you want to make sure that they can get additional
content too. So it's like, get me 10 hooks, shoot this, this, this,
and that. So you almost have to think like, uh, you,
you gotta like leverage them as like your little, your little doers.
Um, so when you get back the content, your editor will know, okay, like,
I have this base style ad and they have a ton of B-roll and ton of hooks for me
that I can chop this up into multiple variations, right?
So you want the ammunition from them. Um, but it starts with the,
with the creative brief.
And even if you want to get on a call with the creator and let them know your
vision, I think that's really important to getting them aligned.
'cause you'll get back some weird ass stuff if you don't do that.
And I've, I've worked with like,
I've dozens and dozens and it's like everyone has different people say they know
what they're doing, but they don't that, did that help answer your question.
And the
Creators always ask for freedom, right? They're like, oh, just let me go do it.
Yeah. And so you can, that's fine, but you need to get this done too. Yeah,
Exactly.
Do this first place.
Yeah.
All right, moving on. Number three, designer. Um,
I personally, I'm a designer myself, so I never hired a designer,
but if you're doing in-house emails, photography, static ads, landing pages,
that kinda stuff, designers are gonna be working around the clock for you. Um,
I don't know if, does anybody have designers right now on their team? Nice.
Yeah. So I don't have too much to say about that, but, um,
an optional hire too is having an animator, like a motion graphic animator,
someone who specializes in two D or three D like,
depending on the ads that you create, like you can, you know,
there's a completely different style of like, motion graphic ads that, you know,
two D three animators could be like pumping out. Um,
lastly,
I think a creative director is someone that you probably wanna hire last.
If you have editors, you have content creators, you have, you know, designers,
the creative director is someone that you basically will help manage all of
these creatives who like, understand the vision,
who understand the media buying, who understand the copywriting,
and then is able to communicate that to all of the creatives. Um,
I think this is like one of the hardest roles to probably like find,
but when you have a strong creative director,
you'll probably be able to kind of remove yourself from the equation.
Not a hundred percent,
but you'll be working directly with like a creative director, uh, of some sort,
um, when you get to that point. But yeah.
Anybody have questions of the creative directors?
I think someone said damn hard to find. Is that what you said?
Yeah, that was dusty.
Yeah, it is hard man. 'cause like you're,
it takes time for someone to really learn your business. Like for us,
it, it took an editor like a year to like really understand what the hell you're
doing. And if you're an agency, you're working with multiple brands and such,
like, man, things are moving so fast, right? And like, and, and,
but I think having someone there who is like kind of absorbing all of the wins
and losses, accumulates that experience over time.
And that's someone you want to like, kind of hold onto 'cause um,
they're gonna be super valuable.
A quick thought on that. Um,
'cause earlier you were talking about hiring qualified people. Um,
just a quick share.
I think it's really important that if anyone is gonna be hiring a creative
manager or creative director,
that that person already has experience in the world of digital marketing and or
media buying. Mm-hmm. And not teaching them that.
Because for six to 12 months you're gonna be pulling your hair out wondering why
they don't know what to do every day. Right.
Whereas skip that step and find someone who's already been exposed to that
world, who has the creative chops like John is sharing. And John,
I'm sure you've been through a similar experience. Oh yeah. Um,
just don't teach them that part. Find the person that has that requirement.
I agree. I agree, man. I, um, I've had few creative directors.
One came from like the TV world, completely different like language and,
and pacing, you know? Mm-hmm. It's like, you know,
people who worked at different agencies,
like those are probably your best betts. Um,
and I'll share a resource where you can find very specific, uh,
hires for this type of role.
One quick thing, dusty, KIPP or Luke, did you guys have questions?
Just wanted to make sure, 'cause I saw the hands there.
Do you wanna do the questions at the end, John? So if we could,
Yeah. Either or just remember it 'cause I'm a d d and I'll forget it.
Awesome. Yeah,
We can definitely touch on those.
All right.
So this is kind of like a basic tree map of what your creative team could look
like. You got you on the top, you got your creative strategist, director,
copywriter, project manager. Like this is that like person right underneath you,
who is your right hand.
And then they will be managing all the indi individual creators under them.
And in the beginning, that will be you, right? Correct.
Until you can hire that creative director.
Yes, exactly. So this is like the cream of a crop.
You're pumping out tons of s**t. Like you are,
you are high volume at that point. Now,
this is a really important thing that I don't think a lot of people talk about,
but hybrid rules, okay? And this is what I learned, you know,
over doing by,
by having a smaller team over the last year and a half is hybrid roles.
So a two person team structure, you know,
you doing everything else plus one editor, right?
Like depending on your skillsets and experience,
like you're just hiring what you don't, what you can't do yourself. Um,
so that could be a very optimal team right there,
like just working hand in hand with your editor, like level leveling them up.
Um,
another two person team structure is like you doing strategy copy,
me buying. Then you're working with someone who has multiple skill sets,
like strategy, uh, who can shoot, who can edit, right?
So depending on the level of skill sets that individual has,
like the more valuable that they become for you. 'cause then you know,
it's one person that you're dealing with versus two.
So I find that if I'm gonna hire, if I'm looking for like a,
like a, like a videographer, like I wanna make sure that they can edit too.
And I wanna make sure that they can potentially script too.
So I'm gonna teach them multiple skills or qualify them first to see if they
have the chops. Um, because that person, you know, output wise, it's like,
okay, we don't need to edit right now. Let's go, let's go do some scripts.
Like let's go copy some ads. Like they can jump around in the business a lot.
And that's really, really valuable, especially if you're running lean
three person team structure. You've got strategy copy, creator and editor.
Um, just another variation of what could be four,
four person team structure, six person team structure.
This is basically you're doubling up on your content creators,
doubling up on your editors.
Um, okay, so where to hire good creatives? Um, if you wanna screenshot this,
basically, I found people on all of these, right?
But there's pros and cons to all of these platforms. Uh,
LinkedIn is a great place. Uh,
I think it's really about how you positioned your messaging in,
in the hiring process. Um,
but there's this other resource. Have you heard of Creative ly?
I was, no, that caught my attention. I've actually never seen that.
All right, you guys need to check this out.
But it's just for creatives and they come from like agency backgrounds.
Like you can find a direct response editor there.
You can find like a creative director who worked on, you know,
who worked on an agency. Like it does cost money to join. I think that's,
that's really what you're paying for premium talent right there.
But the pool is,
is really specific and specialize nice because a lot of these Upwork and online
jobs, you're gonna have to filter through a ton of people, right?
As you guys probably know, there's gold in there. There's,
there's some good people in there. But, um,
if you have the time to sort through it. And then, um,
last thing I wanna bring up is like, you're, you're your warm audience. Like,
um, creatively life. I'll have to double check that. But, um,
one thing too is like just sniping people.
If you find people on like Twitter or Instagram or Facebook and just like, dude,
you, like, if they're an editor or they're posting their own stuff,
just reach out like, Hey dude, I love your work. Like,
is it possible if I can like, get a project with you,
like a test project and just kind of build that relation, like that outreach,
man, I've, I've acquired some good people just from doing that.
You'd be surprised. Um, so keep your eye out.
Like if you're intentional about a hire,
you're gonna attract it into your reality, right? It's like,
I'm looking for this like, show me, show me universe. Um,
alright, so what to pay creatives. And you know,
this is by no means like definitive.
I'm not basing this off of like some sort of chart.
It is just like personal experience here. Um,
but offshore pricing and u s a prices. So, you know,
our junior editors make anywhere between 500 to a thousand a month. Um,
and then us editors, depending on their skill level, right? 35 to five K,
these are us. Like, it, it gets expensive when you're,
when you're working in the us that's,
so it might be best to kind of do offshore initially. Um,
and then yeah, list goes on and on. You guys can take a screenshot of that.
But any questions about this?
Looks good.
Looks good. Cool. So hiring will always depend on your business objectives,
right? Um, like I said, everyone's business is different and you're gonna hire,
some people are gonna need more designers.
Some people are gonna need more videographers or more media buyers,
whatever it is, man, you, you hire for what your business needs.
But you gotta remember, people need to be managed, okay?
So be prepared to take that responsibility on until you hire someone to manage
them like you're entering the people game HR world. Like it's,
uh, it'll be a learning curve, but like I said,
hire slow and I think you guys will do great.
All right. Thank you guys for listening. Sorry if I missed anything.
I know there's a lot to cover in this topic.
Yeah, well done. And you did pretty much right on time, to be honest, actually.
Can all things considered
Awesome. Awesome. Appreciate
It. Um, I, I know Dusty had a question. Luke had a question.
I think Luke or Kip rather had a question as well.
Sweet
Dust. You wanna go first?
Yeah, I'll go. Uh, sure. Yeah, I just had, it was really just real quick.
I mean, you touched on some of the pay there right at the end. Um, we are,
we are, the creative director is kind of the spot that we're really, um,
kind the last link in the chain really for us. You know, there,
we have a guy who, like, he's been writing copy for us for a while.
We've kind of fostered him into writing like video scripts. And then he's been,
he actually takes like the creative direction and orders the,
the actual videos from our team, right? So he's kind of standin,
but he's been a freelancer, right? So like, we're trying to pull him in,
but I didn't notice on on kind of like we have had the conversation with him,
like, so we know like kind of what he's making as a freelancer, uh, you know,
and so to start, to start that there. But like, what do you,
for that position in particular, knowing that it's kind of that middle one, uh,
what do you suggest around like,
as far as a good offering for pay on something like that? Like,
'cause obviously he's, we're trying to get him actually in-house,
so that way it's a little bit more, like you said, stable, um, more control.
But just curious what your thoughts are there.
Yeah. Where's he based out of?
I mean, he is, he's here in the States.
Oh, nice. And um, like how much is he making for you right now?
Well, I mean, from us, uh, but he's like a freelancer. He does some copywriting.
He's looking like to essentially get outta that,
but I think he's in that like low six figures to kind of like,
and he's a freelancer, so he fluctuates like, you know,
110 to like 130 ish a year is kind of what he makes, you know? Yeah. And so,
um, I mean I was trying, I don't imagine that that sounds like too unrealistic,
right? For the kind of the kind of position that we're asking him to come into.
I just didn't know what kind of, you know,
when you guys hire somebody of that nature into your business with that
position, knowing that they're kind of like a critical,
like they're dr they're literally driving the ship, you know? Yeah.
What does that look like?
I mean, yeah, I think it's, it's, um, it can vary, right?
Uh, he, he could be like in a position where it's like,
I don't really want to commit to something full-time, you know?
I like the freelancer position, so in order to kind of convince him like,
you're,
you're probably gonna have to offer him more than what he's already making,
right?
That's kinda what I figured. Yeah. 'cause he, I mean, he is interested,
like he is, he is definitely been like, yeah dude, that'd be cool. Like,
he loves the, this is where he wanted to go, you know,
he's always been a copywriter.
And so like we've given him the ability to kind of bridge into that more
creative side, you know, and kind of content directing, you know,
creative director sort of thing. Um, but that's kind of what my thought was.
And you obviously we're just trying to figure out how to,
as we grow as an agency, does that even make sense to, at,
at least at the stage that we're at?
Should we keep 'em as a freelancer until obviously you're a little bit bigger?
'cause then it's like, you know, some, some of those players,
some of those players, you know, you don't want,
you don't want 'em to be like absolutely just wild on the pay. But then again,
it's like depending on, I guess it's all value, you know, ultimately,
but that it was just cool to hear what your thoughts were.
Yeah, I mean, depending on, I mean, will, did you have some thoughts on that?
'cause it sounded like you did.
Yeah, I mean, in a sub seven figure business,
I think that position needs to be directly tracked towards revenue production.
Like yeah. To me,
I think that position is more of a creative manager position and not a director
position. Uh, you know, creative manager,
you could probably find someone in the 50 to a hundred K range when you're
paying 130 K. I mean, we're talking a five to $10 million a year business,
right? At this point. Like, I,
I don't think a small business can afford to pay someone at that level, uh,
without them being directly tied to the revenue that they're generating from
their role.
Yes. Yeah. That was my first thought was like, you know, I agree.
What if it's like 70? You know,
obviously if that's the kind of thing it was like, well,
I could understand maybe being like, like a,
like a fixed pay of like 70% of that with,
with an incentive to the upside should, you know Yeah.
On that kind of thing or something like that. But, um, but anyways, I mean, I,
and I know from a, like, just from our standpoint,
obviously we're trying to fill that position.
He was kind of our first thought because he's in the mix already, you know,
but you're talking, you know,
obviously there are options out there as far as finding somebody else that maybe
fits a little bit more into where we're at. Um, I mean, we're not,
You can maybe train them,
you could consider you like leveraging him to train the creative manager,
Right? Yeah. That, yeah, that's a good idea. Um, kind of go from there,
but yeah. Cool. Well, I appreciate
It. Yeah. Yeah. My, my question was gonna be like,
how much are you making as a business? Because that, that's a, you know, what,
what Will said, you gotta be, that person has to be generating revenue,
you know, in some way, shape or form because, um, for example, uh,
I dunno if you guys have heard of tube science.com or they're, uh, they're huge.
They used to be huge. They're like, of e-comm bids, but they,
they did like thousands of brand, uh, thousands of, of pieces of content.
They worked with, like Dr. Squash, like huge, huge companies. And they,
they built a hundred thousand square foot, um, uh,
like universal studios Wow. Where they just shot videos and stuff. Um,
and I knew a lot of the, the people who, not a lot,
but I knew some people who worked there as like creative directors and creative
managers, and I asked them like, how much are you getting paid? You know? Um,
and, and one of 'em said, you know, they were making like 70 K a year,
and it was like, that was really solid for them. You know? That's,
that was a really good pay. And they're responsible for a lot of stuff.
And you'd be surprised, um, you know, at that, at that, at that rate.
Like, it, you can get a lot for your money. Um mm-hmm.
So yeah, you have like specialized people. I mean, I think,
I think just depends on your business and you know, where you want to take it.
If that's choice you have to make.
Yeah. I appreciate it. Yeah, we're not, I mean, we're,
we're around like 700 K a year, um, you know, pushing. So that, like, that's,
that's where all that came from. It was like, yeah, this doesn't make, to me,
it doesn't make sense, you know, right now. Uh,
it might make sense when we pushed well into seven figures, you know,
for somebody on that level to be kind of crushing it like that.
So part of me was like, dude, I'm,
I'm glad you're crushing it as a freelancer man. Like,
you should probably keep doing that for a while, you know, like, yeah. Uh,
that sounds great for a copywriter, you know?
Yeah. No, that guy's doing well. Uh, any other questions? Yeah,
I think Joe and Luke,
Yeah. Uh, it's funny that you're on this call today, John.
I've been on your order form.
I've been seeing your ads and about to buy your program.
What's up dude?
Retargeting for probably like two weeks. So let's see if we can All good.
Pass this objection. That's funny. I was thinking about this.
So the way I work is I have me, I have a creative director. Um,
I just went from two to four editors and one graphic designer, uh,
actually two graphic, two graphic designers.
I don't interact with my video editors directly very often. I like hire them,
put 'em in Slack, and then I just, I just let 'em go and,
and then I meet with my creative director and say, Hey, who's doing a good job?
Who's not? Mm-hmm. Um,
how would or how, how have you or how have others?
If I have a training program for video editors, uh,
that helps 'em make better ads, how do I get them to take that,
take action on it, and how do I make sure they're, they're actually doing it?
Uh, they're hourly, so I can say, give this an hour a day. Uh,
but how do I actually make sure they're doing it and using what you teach?
'cause I would like to have better quality, just like 10% better ads coming out.
Yeah. I think it's a great question. And,
and what is your primary focus in the business since you're not communicating
with your editors?
I spend probably two thirds of my time in sales right now.
One third in operations and in operations. I'm just between media buying.
I j only meet with my media buyer and create and creative director.
I don't Got it. I don't, I don't, don't, can't talk to everyone.
Yep. Well done, Joe. Yeah, thanks. I get it. You gotta have your gatekeepers.
Um, what was I gonna say? Um, do you run a brand or an agency?
This is an agency. Okay.
Got it. So I think, you know, in, in your position, there's a lot,
we have a lot of those types of people who bring in their editors into ads orx
training. Right. And they invite their editors into the Slack.
So what happens is, like they,
they're excited because they haven't been taught this stuff and they,
they have someone who's giving them like, live feedback on their videos. Mm-hmm.
Because, you know, if they're not, if,
if they don't have anyone to communicate with and share feedback with,
then it's like, you know, they, they don't know if they're improving. Right.
So we kind of facilitate that and then, you know,
just getting them around other creatives is gonna in, in inspire them,
that's for sure.
Okay, cool. All right. So just get 'em in.
And then y'all have a Slack channel as well that comes with the program,
Correct? Yeah,
Bring 'em all in. Okay, cool. That's another way for me to, like, I,
I have four, I think probably three are gonna make it. So I, like,
I hired two last week. Awesome. I went from two four last week.
'cause I knew I've been through a lot of video editors. Yeah. You know,
you know how it is. Um, and, and yeah, everything from them,
like billing,
three hours for color grading that never needed to be done in the first place to
just not getting things done timely. Like, I've been through a few, so
if I, yeah. Just having better things coming out. That's awesome. I,
I haven't even really looked at your stuff, but your ad spoke directly to me.
Like, whatever your targeting was was very on point. Okay,
Fine. It is, it's all creative, right? It's all messaging. Yeah.
I'll, I'll give it a, I'll give it a try here and see,
give it like a few months and see, uh, see how the results are.
And you didn't even plug it, man. I plugged it for you.
Yeah, I know, right? We, I didn't even ask John for that today.
Just kind of happened. Uh, yeah. One quick thought on that.
Just culture of training and development. You know, like, ha do a,
have your creative director do a,
a training weekly or monthly with the editors and just make it a requirement to
be involved in the business. Okay. Like, hey, if you want more, you,
if you want more work, like you gotta show up to this,
maybe even offer to pay them. I don't know. You'll have to
I'll pay them that, that hour of work. Yeah. Right. It's, it's an hour of work.
Like that's easier than editing videos. Well, I don't know. They're all,
they're also like somewhere, I think I have two in Pakistan, so.
Yeah. Like, I mean, whatever they can show up if they're, if they're serious,
they can show up and if not, they don't. Right.
Yeah. I think they'll, yeah, we can, we can talk about it. And also, you know,
I'm happy to,
to give you guys hookups for sure if you guys have editors and stuff. Um,
because what's, what's really inspiring, like when I saw Will's program,
I was like, there needs to be this, but for creatives and um, like,
you know, everyone here is freaking amazing at what they do,
but it's a completely different conversation when it comes to creative or like
actually doing the work, right.
So I think there's definitely some collaboration opportunities here, for sure.
Absolutely. Mm-hmm. Uh, Luke?
Yeah. First off John, just wanna say excellent presentation. Uh,
definitely related to your story, especially uh,
out in oc I did the same thing Yes. Uh,
in San Diego when I first started making some money. So I can definitely relate.
Uh, your story gives me hope. I'm, uh,
I'm relatively new to the e-comm game.
I've had my company for about two years now. Uh, still a one man show,
like my only employees are customer service. Um,
so my question was around order of hiring some of these creative people, um,
as my revenues have gone up, my creative output has actually gone down.
'cause I've just had so much more responsibilities coming up mm-hmm. Uh,
in developing new products, email marketing, et cetera. Right. Uh,
so my question is, you know, if you are a one man show,
your strength lies in the creatives like,
I would say that's my zone of genius is making the creatives, um,
and all the funnel assets really like the sales pages, et cetera. Um,
would your first hire just be a video editor to help you be more, uh, efficient?
Uh, 'cause I,
my closest friends are actually like all run small media buying agencies.
I've got some like popier homies who can, like,
I've been thinking about just passing it off to them and like just going full in
like, uh, creative, uh, agencies and just passing it off and, uh,
kind of in that debate of, oh, or maybe I hire a video editor,
maybe I build the in-house team. Uh, curious what you would do in my shoes,
given what I just said.
Yeah. You know, I mean, I'm creative agency owner, but I like, I would be like,
hold on, wait a second before you invest in that,
because like ultimately if you,
let's say you hire an editor and I think you should hire an editor,
it's like that becomes an asset for you. A person becomes an asset, right?
Agencies have like all different agendas and different skill sets and stuff like
that. But like if you are training your editor, your vision,
they're going to level up over time.
And that's what I've done with my team is like, they just hear my brain.
They just fricking, you know, oh, I think like John, I think like Luke now. Oh,
that's how Luke wants it. Okay, great. You know,
so then you can communicate your vision, they can do the execution,
you can do the other things in your business.
So I think if you're a creative guy, awesome. Like it's a good, good start.
Cool. Yeah, that makes sense, man. Yeah. Thanks again. Awesome call.
Absolutely. Thank you man. And let's party some time, man. I'm just kidding.
That's funny, David.
Yeah. Um, appreciate it, John. That was a great talk. I also,
you spoke to me also actually kind of on the side where you were saying how now
you've leaned down, you're working with your wife closely.
I'm in a similar boat.
I've actually got burned by partners long ago with an old agency and then now
just have my wife pretty much as a partner in the business.
She has a background in acting, filmmaking, editing, things like that.
So it's like, Hey, why don't we actually leverage what you are good at?
And so she does help do shot, uh, like shot lists,
come up with video shoots and helps produce actual shoots and she can do stuff
like U G C stuff and collaborate with people. What we've been missing,
I think is the translation of like direct response. Mm-hmm.
Unique elements to that.
And so I'm constantly trying to kind of educate her on things.
So she's getting much better at doing stuff that's tilted towards modern
hooks and things like that. But, um, yeah, so I'm interested actually in ads rx,
'cause I saw that training. I was like, oh,
I should just hand her this and we should both just go through that rabbit hole
and get educated on that. Those templates also look awesome,
so I'm definitely interested in that. Um, but for her,
when training somebody who has like a background in traditional video editing
and you are, would you say that that would be like an uh,
kind of a path worth taking if she doesn't necessarily have a background in
direct response? Like something like your program might help her in that?
Yeah, ultimately, yes. Absolutely.
So a creative is gonna be a creative no matter what, right?
And so they're just born with that.
So learning direct response is like learning a additional skillset to your
creative, you know, it's gonna come naturally.
It's just like learning a little bit of a different language, right? And it,
it's, it's like if she's already doing that,
then plugging in direct response style creative like is gonna be, oh,
like the light bulbs are gonna go off.
'cause it really comes down to being able to see what the patterns are,
the structures are, you know, in will's, will's course,
like what blew my mind was like how you structured, like how your hooks,
like your copy, your frameworks. Same thing applies to video, right?
There's frameworks, there's systems to that. And you know, if you're just doing,
doing without really being coach or like,
you don't really know if you're hitting the target, then yeah,
it's just gonna be like, so, so every, every time you produce, but, um, I,
I think you'd love it. Well
Think to that point of John's as well. Um,
eventually later on she'll be able to then manage the execution team members
to the team. So if you guys do take on a couple editors or something,
then she can speak with them on behalf of what it is that you're looking for.
On the performance side, I don't think you can go wrong with any sort of,
you know,
training for the creative side of the team that helps bridge that gap that John
was alluding to earlier between creative team and media buying team and
performance. I, I just don't think you can go wrong there at all.
We always have our creatives join our media buying trainings all the time in our
internal team.
Yeah.
She has a lot of friends in the film space that are always freelancing different
shoots and stuff, and they're, when the season's down, like you're in Vegas,
you know, like let's, certain times of year there's like nothing.
And then it's like,
like trade show season and a lot of commercial shoots and stuff like that.
And they're always looking for like, dang,
what can I fill those slow months with stuff? I'm always telling them like,
okay, you guys have this insane editing and shop production skills. Like,
if you can just attach a little bit of the direct response side,
like there's so many agencies and companies that would,
would absolutely love your services.
Yeah, so true.
Yeah. It's, it's just not taught anywhere. So, you know,
I think filmmakers and stuff are missing out on a big opportunity and brands are
so hungry for it, you know, and there's just not enough,
there's not enough people who know it.
Yep. I would agree with that as well. Yeah. Mm-hmm. Man,
what a great session today. I think it was, uh,
you did an amazing job breaking everything down.
I really appreciate you sharing all of your, your mistakes, uh,
and your learnings and all of that with the group. Absolutely. Pleasures always.
We always love having you back. Um,
we'll have to do it again in a few months time as well, for sure. Uh, any,
any other parting words, uh,
that you would share with the group to wrap us up for today?
Um, first off, just wanna thank you, will appreciate you reaching out. You know,
it's been a, definitely a misconnection for a minute. Um, but uh,
I just wanna say I'm here of resource to anybody, um,
in conjunction with Will and what he teaches. I'm a huge proponent of like,
like all of his methods. And I think translating, like,
I want to be the bridge from media buyer to creative.
Like that's kind of my mission. And so whatever you guys need, I got you. And,
um, just thankful appreciate everybody.
Awesome. Yeah man. Thanks for being here.
Absolutely. All right, all guys. Thanks
Guys. Appreciate you all. Um, catch you tomorrow or later on in Slack.
If you guys have anything you wanna follow up on or jam on, give us a shout.
I'll catch you soon.
Have a good day. Bye bye.